<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AspNetCore on Moien Tajik</title><link>/tags/aspnetcore/</link><description>Recent content in AspNetCore on Moien Tajik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0330</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aspnetcore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>API Versioning in ASP.NET Core</title><link>/posts/2018-11-12-aspnetcore-api-versioning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0330</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-11-12-aspnetcore-api-versioning/</guid><description>This article guides on implementing API versioning in ASP.NET Core, highlighting its simplicity compared to ASP.NET Web API. It covers installing the &lt;code>Microsoft.AspNetCore.Mvc.Versioning&lt;/code> package, setting up default versioning, and various versioning methods including &lt;strong>URL path segment&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>header versioning&lt;/strong>. &lt;br>&lt;br> The article also discusses deprecating older API versions and excluding specific controllers from versioning using the &lt;code>ApiVersionNeutral&lt;/code> attribute. The process is illustrated with concise examples and code snippets, offering a practical approach to API versioning in ASP.NET Core applications.</description></item><item><title>Route constraints in ASP.NET Core</title><link>/posts/2018-11-09-aspnetcore-route-constraints/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0330</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-11-09-aspnetcore-route-constraints/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article covers implementing &lt;strong>route constraints&lt;/strong> in ASP.NET Core to validate route parameter values. It highlights two methods:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol> &lt;li>Inline constraints: using route templates directly&lt;/li> &lt;li>MapRoute constraints: using classes that follow the &lt;code>IRouteConstraint&lt;/code> interface&lt;/li> &lt;/ol>
The article also describes creating custom constraints for specific validation needs, such as checking if a string starts with a particular value. This feature in ASP.NET Core ensures that only valid values are passed to action methods, enhancing API reliability and functionality.</description></item></channel></rss>